Alejandro Rios

Austin TX 956-529-6849

alx.rios91@gmail.com https://www.github.com/arios91 https://www.alex-rios.me

Summary

Software Engineer based in Austin with over five years of experience in designing, developing, testing, and maintaining Java enterprise applications. Proficient in creating business applications using Java as well as front end development using JavaScript frameworks such as React and Angular along with Node.js and Express.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Texas Rio Grande Valley Class of December 2015 Overall GPA: 3.23 Edinburg, TX

Experience

Software Engineer II

Samsung Austin Semiconductor

September 2019 – Current Austin, TX

- Manage and optimize databases responsible for the whole production process, efficient production and operation of products.
- Design and establish efficient systems to improve productivity and product quality while maintaining system reliability.
- Provide technical support for internal users.

Software Engineer

Conduent

Engineer March 2019 – September 2019 Austin, TX

- Tasked with providing support and resolving any issues in Struts backend of medical record system.
- Responsible for migrating legacy Struts project to modern React framework.
- Design and create REST API to be used alongside React system.
- Write unit and functional tests for React application.

Application Developer

May 2016 – March 2019 McAllen, TX

Heroku

Hamer Enterprises

- Provide ongoing development and maintenance for Java payment and billing system.
- Responsible for redesigning and updating legacy projects to be mobile-friendly.
- Ensure Java projects are up to date with all requirements needed to comply with strict ADA regulations.
- Responsible for designing and developing an administrator permissions systems.
- Provide technical support for customers using payment and billing systems.
- Create and maintain required SQL database tables for web applications.

Technical Skills

•	Java	•	JavaScript	•	React
•	JSF	•	Angular	•	MongoDB

PL/SQL • Node.js

HTML/CSS • Express • IBM Db2

PrimeFaces • Firebase • IBM WebSphere